<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chee Wei Tan's Homepage</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Chee Wei Tan's Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cheewtan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Home Content</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/homepage/home-contents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/homepage/home-contents/</guid><description>Dr. Tan received the M.A and Ph.D. degrees in Electrical Engineering from Princeton University. He was a Senior Fellow of the Institute for Pure and Applied Mathematics (IPAM) for the program on Science at Extreme Scales, and was a Postdoctoral Scholar in the NetLab Group at Caltech. His industrial experience includes consulting for Tencent AI Lab, Qualcomm R&amp;amp;D (QRC), Fraser Research Lab. His research interests are optimization of networks, distributed machine learning, cloud computing and AI.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/publications/</guid><description>GitHub Open-source (https://github.com/convexsoft/AITIP) Automated Information Theory Inequality Prover (Software-as-a-Service to Interactively Prove Theorems) Software-as-a-Service Platform freely-available, and is now open-source (Github link in publication below).
AITIP: Automated Information Theoretic Inequalities Prover, IEEE Information Theory Society Newsletter, June 2020
Proving and Disproving Information Inequalities: Theory and Scalable Algorithms, IEEE Transactions on Information Theory, September 2020
Journal M. F. Wong, S. Guo, C.-N. Hang, S.-W. Ho, C. W. Tan, Natural Language Generation and Understanding on Big Code for AI-assisted Programming: A Review, Entropy, Special issue on Statistical Machine Learning with High-Dimensional Data Analysis, minor revision, 2023.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/research/</guid><description>Postdoctoral Fellow and Ph.D. student openings: (1) Convex optimization and distributed machine learning (2) Artificial Intelligence in Networks (e.g., Large Language Models for wireless and social networks) Candidates are expected to be proficient in mathematics (e.g., linear algebra, convex optimization) and have good software programming experience. Please email at cheewei.tan @ ntu.edu.sg with CV and transcripts. (1) Large Language Model Research: AI-assisted Programming Our research explores the applications of Gen-AI technologies, employing large language models to tackle various challenges.</description></item><item><title>Short Introduction</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/homepage/short-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/homepage/short-introduction/</guid><description>Research interests are optimization of networks, distributed machine learning, cloud computing and AI.</description></item><item><title>Teaching</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/teaching-and-outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/teaching-and-outreach/</guid><description>Teaching 1. Convex Optimization and its Applications in Computer Science Course Webpage, project ref: Extremely short linear program solvers.
2. Artificial Intelligence: Past, Present, Future | Introduction | Lec 1 Birth of AI | Lec 2 Mathematical Logic in AI | Lec 3 AI Games | Lec 4 AI Games and Search | Lec 5Maze-Solving and Retros | Lec 6 Human-assisted Computation | Lec 7 Robots | Lec 8 AI Chatbots | Lec 9 Neural Network Applications | Lec 10 Automated Reasoning | Lec 11Machine Learning | Lec 13 Review 3.</description></item></channel></rss>