<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chee Wei Tan's Homepage</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Chee Wei Tan's Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cheewtan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Home Content</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/homepage/home-contents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/homepage/home-contents/</guid><description>Dr. Tan received the M.A and Ph.D. degrees in Electrical Engineering from Princeton University. He was a Senior Fellow of the Institute for Pure and Applied Mathematics (IPAM) for the program on Science at Extreme Scales, and was a Postdoctoral Scholar in the NetLab Group at Caltech. His industrial experience includes consulting for Tencent AI Lab, Qualcomm R&amp;amp;D (QRC), Fraser Research Lab. His research interests are optimization of networks, distributed machine learning, cloud computing and AI.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/publications/</guid><description>Journal M. F. Wong, S. Guo, C.-N. Hang, S.-W. Ho, C. W. Tan, Natural Language Generation and Understanding on Big Code for AI-assisted Programming: A Review, Entropy, Special issue on Statistical Machine Learning with High-Dimensional Data Analysis, minor revision, 2023. C. W. Tan and P. D. Yu, Contagion Source Detection in Epidemic and Infodemic Outbreaks: Mathematical Analysis and Network Algorithms, Foundations and Trends in Networking, Vol. 13, No. 2-3, pp. 107-251, Now Publishers, 2023.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/research/</guid><description>(1) Artificial Intelligence to Advance Health Informatics When the COVID-19 pandemic hit, the epidemic spread outpaced contact tracing efforts, leading to lockdowns and sufferings. Can Artificial Intelligence (AI) prevent the next epidemic, especially the more-deadly Disease X? Can AI-driven contact tracing strategies learn from past superspreading outbreaks to control future epidemics? To advance health informatics is one of the U.S. National Academy of Engineering Grand Challenges. In [1-4], we examine how network science, big data analytics and machine learning can address large-scale problems such as digital contact tracing and Infodemic management using COVID-19 data.</description></item><item><title>Short Introduction</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/homepage/short-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/homepage/short-introduction/</guid><description>Research interests are optimization of networks, distributed machine learning, cloud computing and AI.</description></item><item><title>Software and Openings</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/software-and-openings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/software-and-openings/</guid><description>Ph.D. student openings: (1) Distributed machine learning and optimization
(2) Artificial Intelligence technologies (e.g., AI chatbot, AI cloud computing)
Candidates are expected to be proficient in mathematics (e.g., linear algebra, discrete math like graph theory) and have good software programming experience. Please email at cheewtan @ cityu.edu.hk with CV and transcripts. Automated Information Theory Inequality Prover (Software-as-a-Service to Interactively Prove Theorems) Software-as-a-Service Platform freely-available, and is now open-source (Github link in publication below).</description></item><item><title>Teaching and Outreach</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/teaching-and-outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/teaching-and-outreach/</guid><description>Teaching 1. Convex Optimization and its Applications in Computer Science Course Webpage, project ref: Extremely short linear program solvers.
2. Artificial Intelligence: Past, Present, Future | Introduction | Lec 1 Birth of AI | Lec 2 Mathematical Logic in AI | Lec 3 AI Games | Lec 4 AI Games and Search | Lec 5Maze-Solving and Retros | Lec 6 Human-assisted Computation | Lec 7 Robots | Lec 8 AI Chatbots | Lec 9 Neural Network Applications | Lec 10 Automated Reasoning | Lec 11Machine Learning | Lec 13 Review 3.</description></item></channel></rss>