<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chee Wei Tan's Homepage</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Chee Wei Tan's Homepage</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cheewtan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Home Content</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/homepage/home-contents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/homepage/home-contents/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dr. Tan received the M.A and Ph.D. degrees in Electrical Engineering from &lt;a href="http://www.princeton.edu/">Princeton University&lt;/a>. He is currently with College of Computing and Data Science, Nanyang Technological University in Singapore. He was a postdoctoral scholar in the &lt;a href="http://netlab.caltech.edu/">NetLab Group&lt;/a> at Caltech, a senior fellow of the &lt;a href="https://www.ipam.ucla.edu/">Institute for Pure and Applied Mathematics (IPAM)&lt;/a> for the program Science at Extreme Scales, and was a visiting faculty at Tencent AI Lab and Qualcomm R&amp;amp;D (QRC). His research interests are distributed optimization, Generative AI, networks and edge learning. His Erdös number is 3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/publications/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="journal">Journal&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>L. Chen, D. Zhao, L. Tao, K. Wang, S. Qian, X. Zeng and C. W. Tan, A Credible and Fair Federated Learning Framework Based on Blockchain, IEEE Transactions on Artificial Intelligence, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Jiang, J. Shen, Z. Liu, C. W. Tan, K.-Y. Lam, Towards Efficient and Certified Recovery from Poisoning Attacks in Federated Learning, IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics &amp;amp; Security, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Zhang, T. Gao, C. Li and C. W. Tan, Coded Federated Learning for Communication-Efficient Edge Computing: A Survey, IEEE Open Journal of the Communications Society, Vol. 5, pp. 4098-4124, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Tao, Y. Lu, Y. Fan, L. Shi, C. W. Tan, Z. Wei, Throughput-Scalable Shard Reorganization Tailored to Node Relations in Sharding Blockchain Networks, IEEE Transactions on Computational Social Systems, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. Chen, C. W. Tan, X. Zhai and H. V. Poor, OpenRANet: Neuralized Spectrum Access by Joint Subcarrier and Power Allocation with Optimization-based Deep Learning, IEEE Transactions on Green Communications and Networking, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Chen, W. Zhang, C. Dong, D. Zhao, X. Zeng, S. Qiao, Y. Zhu, C. W. Tan, FedTKD: A Trustworthy Heterogeneous Federated Learning Based on Adaptive Knowledge Distillation, Entropy, 26(1), 96, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Chen, W. Zhang, C. Dong, Z. Huang, Y. Nie, Z. Hou, S. Qiao, C. W. Tan, FedDRL: Trustworthy Federated Learning Model Fusion Method Based on Staged Reinforcement Learning, Computing and Informatics, 43(1): pp. 1-37, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>D. T. K. Ng, C. W. Tan, J. K. L Leung, Empowering Student Self-regulated Learning and Science Education through ChatGPT: A Pioneering Pilot Study, British Journal of Educational Technology, Vol. 55, Issue 4, pp. 1328-1353, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. N. Hang, P. D. Yu and C. W. Tan, MCQGen: A Large Language Model-Driven MCQ Generator for Personalized Learning, IEEE Access, Vol. 12, pp. 102261-102273, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>J.-Y. Zeng, F.-H. Tseng and C. W. Tan, Physical Adversarial Example in Car Plate Recognition Systems based on SA Algorithm, IEEE Consumer Electronics Magazine, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>M. F. Wong, S. Guo, C.-N. Hang, S.-W. Ho and C. W. Tan, Natural Language Generation and Understanding of Big Code for AI-Assisted Programming: A Review, Entropy, 25(6): 888, 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>P. D. Yu, C. W. Tan, L. Zheng and C. Zhao, Unraveling Contagion Origins: Optimal Estimation through Maximum-Likelihood and Starlike Graph Approximation in Markovian Spreading Models, IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing, under review, 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan and P. D. Yu, Contagion Source Detection in Epidemic and Infodemic Outbreaks: Mathematical Analysis and Network Algorithms, Foundations and Trends in Networking, Vol. 13, No. 2-3, pp. 107-251, Now Publishers, 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. N. Hang, P. D. Yu, S. Chen, C. W. Tan and G. Chen, MEGA: Machine Learning-Enhanced Graph Analytics for Infodemic Risk Management, IEEE Journal of Biomedical and Health Informatics, Vol. 27, No. 12, pp. 6100-6111, 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. N. Hang, Y.-Z. Tsai, P.-D. Yu, J. Chen, C. W. Tan, Privacy-Enhancing Digital Contact Tracing with Machine Learning for Pandemic Response: A Comprehensive Review, Big Data and Cognitive Computing, Special issue on digital health and data analytics in public health, Vol. 7, No. 2, 108, 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. Li, Y. Zhang and C. W. Tan, Fault-Tolerant Computation Meets Network Coding: Optimal Scheduling in Parallel Computing, IEEE Transactions on Communications, Vol. 71, No. 7, pp. 3847-3860, 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Zhang, C. Li and C. W. Tan, On Symmetric Multilevel Diversity Coding System with Linear Computations, IEEE Communications Letter, Vol. 27, No. 8, pp. 1994-1998, 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan and P. D. Yu, Contagion Source Detection in Epidemic and Infodemic Outbreaks: Mathematical Analysis and Network Algorithms, Foundations and Trends in Networking, Vol. 13, No. 2-3, pp. 107-251, Now Publishers, 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. N. Hang, P. D. Yu, S. Chen, C. W. Tan and G. Chen, MEGA: Machine Learning-Enhanced Graph Analytics for Infodemic Risk Management, IEEE Journal of Biomedical and Health Informatics, accepted and to appear, 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. N. Hang, Y.-Z. Tsai, P.-D. Yu, J. Chen, C. W. Tan, Privacy-Enhancing Digital Contact Tracing with Machine Learning for Pandemic Response: A Comprehensive Review, Big Data and Cognitive Computing, Special issue on digital health and data analytics in public health, accepted and to appear, 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. Li, Y. Zhang and C. W. Tan, Fault-Tolerant Computation Meets Network Coding: Optimal Scheduling in Parallel Computing, IEEE Transactions on Communications, accepted and to appear, 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>M. F. Wong, X. Qi and C. W. Tan, EuclidNet: Deep Visual Reasoning for Constructible Problems in Geometry, Advances in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, Vol. 3, No. 1, pp. 839-852, 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>P. Yu, C. W. Tan and H. L. Fu, &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2201.06751">Epidemic Source Detection in Contact Tracing Networks: Epidemic Centrality in Graphs and Message-Passing Algorithms&lt;/a>, IEEE Journal on Selected Topics in Signal Processing, Vol. 16, No. 2, pp. 234-249, 2022.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Z. Fei, Y. Ryeznik, O. Sverdlov, C. W. Tan and W. K. Wong, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/IEEETransBigDataCOVID19.pdf">An Overview of Healthcare Data Analytics with Applications to the COVID-19 Pandemic&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Big Data, Vol. 8, No. 6, pp. 1463-1480, 2022.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, The Value of Cooperation: From AIMD to Flipped Classroom Teaching, ACM SIGMETRICS Performance Evaluation Review, Vol. 49, No. 4, pp. 8-13, 2022.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. W. Ho, L. Ling, C. W. Tan and R. W. Yeung, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/titaitip.pdf">Proving and Disproving Information Inequalities: Theory and Scalable Algorithms&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Information Theory, Vol. 66, No. 9, pp. 5522-5536, 2020.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. Liu, C. Joe-Wong, J. Chen, C. Brinton, C. W. Tan and L. Zheng, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/GoogleFi.pdf">Economic Viability of a Virtual ISP&lt;/a>, IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, Vol. 28, No. 2, pp. 902-916, 2020.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>P.-D. Yu, C. W. Tan and H. Fu, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/jstsp2018.pdf">Averting Cascading Failures in Networked Infrastructures: Poset-constrained Graph Algorithms&lt;/a>, IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Signal Processing, Vol. 12, No. 4, pp.733-748, 2018.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. Li, X. Guang, C. W. Tan and R. W. Yeung, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/jsacsecrecy.pdf">Fundamental Limits on a Class of Secure Asymmetric Multilevel Diversity Coding Systems&lt;/a>, IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communication, Vol. 36, No. 4, pp. 737-747, 2018.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>D. Li, X. Guang, Z. Zhou, C. Li and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/networkcoding.pdf">Hierarchical Performance Analysis on Random Linear Network Coding&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Communications, Vol. 66, No. 5, pp.2009-2021, 2018.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng, D. Cai and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7913642">Max-min Fairness Rate Control in Wireless Networks: Optimality and Algorithms by Perron-Frobenius Theory&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing, Vol. 17, No. 1, pp.127-140, 2018.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng, C. Joe-Wong, C. W. Tan, S. Ha and M. Chiang, Customized Data Plans for Mobile Users: Feasibility and Benefits of Data Trading, IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communication, Vol. 35, No. 4, pp. 949-963, 2017.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>F. M. F. Wong, C. W. Tan, S. Sen and M. Chiang, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TweetRetweet.pdf">Quantifying Political Leaning from Tweets, Retweets and Retweeters&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering, Vol. 28, No. 8, pp. 2158-2172, 2016.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng, C. Joe-Wong, C. W. Tan, M. Chiang and X. Wang, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/sigcomm.pdf">How to Bid the Cloud?&lt;/a>, ACM SIGCOMM Computer Communication Review, Vol. 45, No. 5, pp. 71-84, 2015.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanTon2015.pdf">Optimal Power Control in Rayleigh-fading Heterogeneous Wireless Networks&lt;/a>, IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, Vol. 24, No. 2, pp. 940-953, 2016.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng, Y. W. Hong, C. W. Tan, C. L. Hsieh and C. H. Lee, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TIT2016.pdf">Wireless Max-min Utility Fairness with General Monotonic Constraints by Perron-Frobenius Theory&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Information Theory, Vol. 62, No. 12, pp. 7283-7298, 2016.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Gao, C. W. Tan, Y. Huang, Z. Zeng and P. R. Kumar, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TMC2016.pdf">Characterization and Optimization of Delay Guarantees for Real-time Multimedia Traffic Flows in IEEE802.11 WLANs&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing, Vol. 15, No. 5, pp. 1090-1104, 2016. &lt;/li>
&lt;li>Z. Wang, W. Dong, W. Zhang and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/RumorDetectionJSTSP.pdf">Rooting out Rumor Sources in Online Social Networks: The Value of Diversity from Multiple Observations&lt;/a>, IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Signal Processing, special issue on signal processing for big data, Vol. 9, No. 4, pp. 663-677, 2015. &lt;a href="http://www.technologyreview.com/view/510661/other-interesting-arxiv-papers-this-week">Highlighted by MIT Technology Review Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I.-W. Lai, L. Zheng, C.-H. Lee and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/LaiZhengLeeTan_JSAC_2014.pdf">Beamforming Duality and Algorithms for Weighted Sum Rate Maximization in Cognitive Radio Networks&lt;/a>, IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications, Vol. 33, No. 5, pp. 832-847, 2015.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, D. W. H. Cai and Lou, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/OPF.pdf">Resistive Network Optimal Power Flow: Uniqueness and Algorithms&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Power Systems, Vol. 30, No. 1, pp. 263-273, 2015.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>N. Chen, C. W. Tan and T. Quek, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/EValley.pdf">Electric Vehicle Charging in Smart Grid: Optimality and Valley-Filling Algorithms&lt;/a>, IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Signal Processing, Vol. 8, No. 6, pp. 1073-1083, 2014.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lou and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/optenergystorage.pdf">Optimization Decomposition of Resistive Power Networks with Energy Storage&lt;/a>, IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications, Vol. 32, No. 7, pp. 1371-1385, 2014.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lou, H. Yao, C. W. Tan and J. Wang, VANDER: Efficient Cooperative Watchdog Monitoring for Lossy Wireless Network Coding, IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology, Vol. 64, No. 2, pp. 702-713, 2014.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>X. Zhai, L. Zheng and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/ZhaiZhengTanJSAC2014.pdf">Energy-Infeasibility Tradeoff in Cognitive Radio Networks: Price-Driven Spectrum Access Algorithms&lt;/a>, IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications, Vol. 32, No. 3, pp. 528-538, 2014.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/ZhengTanJSAC2014.pdf">Maximizing Sum Rates in Cognitive Radio Networks: Convex Relaxation and Global Optimization Algorithms&lt;/a>, IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications, Vol. 32, No. 3, pp. 667-680, 2014.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/ZhengTanTWC.pdf">Optimal Algorithms in Wireless Utility Maximization: Proportional Fairness Decomposition and Nonlinear Perron-Frobenius Theory Framework&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Wireless Communications, Vol. 13, No. 4, pp. 2086-2095, 2014.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng and C. W. Tan, Egalitarian Fairness Framework for Joint Rate and Power Optimization in Wireless Networks, ACM SIGMETRICS Performance Evaluation Review, Vol. 42, No. 2, pp. 58-60, 2014.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/ZT2013.pdf">Cognitive Radio Network Duality and Algorithms for Utility Maximization&lt;/a>, IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications, Vol. 31, No. 3, pp. 500-513, 2013.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, M. Chiang and R. Srikant, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanChiangSrikant_ToN.pdf">Fast Algorithms and Performance Bounds for Sum Rate Maximization in Wireless Networks&lt;/a>, IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, Vol. 21, No. 3, pp. 706-719, 2013.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Huang, C. W. Tan and B. D. Rao, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/HuangTanRao_TWC2012.pdf">Joint Beamforming and Power Control in Coordinated Multicell: Max-min Duality, Effective Network and Large System Transition&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Wireless Communications, Vol. 12, No. 6, pp. 2730-2742, 2013.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Yang, H. Kim, J. Zhang, M. Chiang and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/YangKimZhangChiangTan_ToN.pdf">Pricing-based Decentralized Spectrum Access Control in Cognitive Radio Networks&lt;/a>, IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, Vol. 21, No. 2, pp. 522-535, 2013.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. Sorooshyari, C. W. Tan and M. Chiang, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/SorooshyariTanChiang_TON2012.pdf">Power Control for Cognitive Radio Networks: Axioms, Algorithms, and Analysis&lt;/a>, IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, Vol. 20, No. 3, pp. 878-891, 2012.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>D. W. H. Cai, T. Quek, C. W. Tan and S. H. Low, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/SP_2011.pdf">Max-Min SINR Coordinated Multipoint Downlink Transmission - Duality and Algorithms&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing, Vol. 60, No. 10, pp. 5384-5396, 2012.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Zhao, C. W. Tan, A. S. Avestimehr, S. N. Diggavi and G. J. Pottie, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/ZTADP_IT.pdf">On the Maximum Achievable Sum-rate with Successive Decoding in Interference Channels&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Information Theory, Vol. 58, No. 6, pp. 3798-3820, 2012.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, S. Friedland and S. H. Low, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanFriedlandLow-SIAM2011.pdf">Nonnegative Matrix Inequalities and Their Application to Nonconvex Power Control Optimization&lt;/a>, SIAM Journal on Matrix Analysis and Applications, Vol. 32, No. 3, pp. 1030-1055, 2011.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, M. Chiang and R. Srikant, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanChiangSrikant_TSP2011.pdf">Maximizing Sum Rate and Minimizing MSE on Multiuser Downlink: Optimality, Fast Algorithms, and Equivalence via Max-min SINR&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing, Vol. 59, No. 12, pp. 6127-6143, 2011.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>M. Wang, C. W. Tan, W. Xu and A. Tang, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/WangTanXuTang_ToN2011.pdf">Cost of Not Splitting in Routing: Characterization and Estimation&lt;/a>, IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, Vol. 19, No. 6, pp. 1849-1859, 2011.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>D. W. H. Cai, T. Quek and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/CaiQuekTan_TSP2011.pdf">A Unified Analysis of Max-Min Weighted SINR for MIMO Downlink System&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing, Vol. 59, No. 8, pp. 3850-3862, 2011.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, S. Friedland and S. H. Low, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanFriedlandLow-JSAC2011.pdf">Spectrum Management in Multiuser Cognitive Wireless Networks: Optimality and Algorithm&lt;/a>, IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications, Vol. 29, No. 2, pp. 421-430, 2011.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. Sorooshyari, C. W. Tan and H. V. Poor, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/SorooshyariTanPoor_IEEETVT_2010.pdf">On Maximum-Likelihood SINR Estimation of MPSK in a Multiuser Fading Channel&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology, Vol. 59, No. 8, pp. 4175-4181, 2010.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan and A. R. Calderbank, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanCalderbank-TCom-09.pdf">Multiuser Detection of Alamouti Signals&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Communications, Vol. 57, No. 7, pp. 2080-2089, 2009.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, D. P. Palomar and M. Chiang, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanPalomarChiang_TransNetworking2008.pdf">Energy-Robustness Tradeoff in Cellular Network Power Control&lt;/a>, IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, Vol. 17, No. 3, pp. 912-925, 2009.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>M. Chiang, C. W. Tan, D. P. Palomar, D. O&amp;rsquo;Neill and D. Julian, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/ChiangTanPalomarOneillJulian_TransWireless_2007.pdf">Power Control by Geometric Programming&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Wireless Communications, Vol. 6, No. 7, pp. 2640-2651, 2007.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, D. M. Chiu, John C. S. Lui and K. Yau, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanChiuLuiYau_TransParallel_2007.pdf">A Distributed Throttling Approach for Handling High Bandwidth Aggregates&lt;/a>, IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems, Vol. 18, No. 7, pp. 983-995, 2007.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, G. Mohan and John C. S. Lui, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanMohanLui_JSAC_2006.pdf">Achieving Multi-Class Service Differentiation in WDM Optical Burst Switching Networks: A Probabilistic Preemptive Burst Segmentation Scheme&lt;/a>, IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications, Vol. 24, No. 12, pp. 106-119, 2006.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="monographs-and-edited-books">Monographs and Edited Books&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan (Ed.), &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Online-Social-Networks-Perspectives-Applications/dp/1536173878">Online Social Networks: Perspectives, Applications and Developments&lt;/a>, Nova Science Publishers, 2020.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Wireless_Network_Optimization_by_Perron_Frobenius_Theory.pdf">Wireless Network Optimization by Perron-Frobenius Theory&lt;/a>, Foundations and Trends in Networking, Now Publishers, ISBN 978-1-680830507, 2015.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan (Ed.), &lt;a href="https://novapublishers.com/shop/cognitive-radio-networks-performance-applications-and-technology">Cognitive Radio Networks: Performance, Applications and Technology&lt;/a>, Nova Science Publishers, 2017.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>M. Chiang, P. Hande, T. Lan, C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://www.princeton.edu/~chiangm/powercontrol.pdf">Power Control in Wireless Cellular Networks&lt;/a>, Foundations and Trends in Networking, Now Publishers, ISBN: 978-1-60198-136-3, 2008.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="conference">Conference&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>M. F. Wong and C. W. Tan, Aligning Crowd-sourced Human Feedback for Code Generation with Bayesian Inference, 2024 IEEE Conference on Artificial Intelligence (CAI), 2024 (Honorable Mention Paper Award in Foundation Models and Generative AI Category).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Md T. R. Laskar, S. Alqahtani, M. S. Bari, M. Rahman, M. A. M. Khan, H. Khan, I. Jahan, Md A. H. Bhuiyan, C. W. Tan, Md R. Parvez, E. Hoque, S. Joty and X. Huang, A Systematic Survey and Critical Review on Evaluating Large Language Models: Challenges, Limitations, and Recommendations, The 2024 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2024.  &lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. Hang, P.-D. Yu and C. W. Tan, TrumorGPT: Query Optimization and Semantic Reasoning for Automated Fact-checking, 58th Conference on Information Sciences and Systems (CISS), 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>P.-D. Yu, L. Zheng and C. W. Tan, Contagion Source Detection by Maximum Likelihood Estimation and Starlike Graph Approximation, 58th Conference on Information Sciences and Systems (CISS), 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. Chen and C. W. Tan, Neural Sum Rate Maximization for AI-Native Wireless Networks: Alternating Direction Method of Multipliers Framework and Algorithm Unrolling, ACM MobiSys 2024 International Workshop on Networked AI Systems, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>H. Liang, Z. Zhan, W. Liu, X. Zhang, C. W. Tan and X. Chen, FedReMa: Improving Personalized Federated Learning via Leveraging the Most Relevant Clients, 27th European Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>T. Gao, J. Lin, C. Li and C. W. Tan, Federated Learning Meets Network Coding: Efficient Coded Hierarchical Federated Learning, IEEE Information Theory Workshop, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Jiang, C. W. Tan and K.-Y. Lam, Accelerating Federated Unlearning via Polyak Heavy Ball Method, IEEE Information Theory Workshop, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>K. Wang, C. W. Tan and C. Brinton, Maximizing User Admittance for Cognitive Radio using ODE-inspired Spectral Radius Estimation, IEEE Information Theory Workshop, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. Zhao, Z. Wang, Q. Zhou, C. W. Tan and C. Chan, Infodemic Source Detection: Enhanced Formulations with Information Flow, IEEE International Symposium on Information Theory (ISIT), 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. Fu, X. Zhai, C. Yi, L. Pang and C. W. Tan, Energy Efficient and Low Latency Computation Offloading via Truly PPO in Mobile Edge Computing Networks with Multi-UAV, The 17th IEEE International Conference on Internet of Things (iThings), 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Wang, S. Guo, L. Ling and C. W. Tan, Nemobot: Crafting Strategic Gaming LLM Agents for K-12 AI Education, ACM Learning at Scale, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. C. Fung, M. F. Wong and C. W. Tan, Automatic Feedback Generation on K-12 Students&amp;rsquo; Data Science Education by Prompting Cloud-based Large Language Models, ACM Learning at Scale, 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, Flipped Classroom Teaching with Large Language Models: Peer Instruction and Just-in-Time Teaching, IEEE CAI 2024 Workshop on AI for Education: Exploring LLMs and Adaptive Learning for Personalized Education (CAI'24-AI4EDU), 2024.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, S. Guo, M. F. Wong, Copilot for Xcode: Exploring AI-Assisted Programming by Prompting Cloud-based Large Language Models, Symposium on Large Language Models (LLM 2023), 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. Chen and C. W. Tan, Neural Sum Rate Maximization with Deep Unrolling, IEEE Global Communications (Globecom), 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. Zhang, D. Song, C. W. Tan and C. Li, Predictive Beam Tracking in ISAC Based on Transceiver Division Structure, 21st International Symposium on Modeling and Optimization in Mobile, Ad Hoc, and Wireless Networks (WiOpt), 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>K. Zhao, X. Bryce Zhai, J. Zhu and C. W. Tan, Formation Control Optimization via Virtual Leader Exploration with Deep Reinforcement Learning for Unmanned Aerial Vehicles, IEEE 29th International Conference on Parallel and Distributed Systems (ICPADS), 2023.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>M. F. Wong, X. Qi and C. W. Tan, EuclidNet: Deep Visual Reasoning for Constructible Problems in Geometry, 36th Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) Workshop on Math-AI: Toward Human-Level Mathematical Reasoning, 2022.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. Chen, P.-D. Yu, C. W. Tan and H. V. Poor, Identifying the Superspreader in Proactive Backward Contact Tracing by Deep Learning, 56th Conference on Information Sciences and Systems (CISS), 2022.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>J. Li, C. W. Tan, C. Hang and X. Qi, A Chatbot-Server Framework for Scalable Machine Learning Education through Crowdsourced Data, ACM Learning at Scale, 2022.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>J. Li, L. Ling and C. W. Tan, Blending Peer Instruction with Just-In-Time Teaching: Jointly Optimal Task Scheduling with Feedback for Classroom Flipping, ACM Learning at Scale, 2021.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Ling and C. W. Tan, Peer-Grading at Scale with Rank Aggregation, ACM Learning at Scale, 2021.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, The Value of Cooperation: From AIMD to Flipped Classroom Teaching, IFIP Performance First International Workshop on Teaching Performance Analysis of Computer Systems, 2021.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. Li, C. W. Tan, J. Li and S. Chen, Fault-Tolerant Computation Meets Network Coding: Optimal Scheduling in Parallel Computing, IEEE Globecom 2021.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>D. Song, X. Zhai, X. Liu and C. W. Tan, Jointly Optimal Fair Data Collection and Trajectory Design Algorithms in UAV-Aided Cellular Networks. IEEE WCNC 2021.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, P. Yu, L. Ling, C. N. Hang and M. F. Wong, Mathematics Gamification in Mobile App Software for Personalized Learning at Scale, IEEE Integrated STEM Education Conference, 2020.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan and L. Ling, Automated Reasoning by Convex Optimization: Proof Simplicity, Duality and Sparsity, 54th CISS 2020 (invited Paper).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, L. Ling, P.-D. Yu, C. N. Hang and M. F. Wong, Mathematics Gamification in Mobile App Software for Personalized Learning at Scale, IEEE Integrated STEM Education Conference, 2020.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Ling and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/LingTanHoYeungISIT_2019.pdf">Scalable Automated Proving of Information Theoretic Inequalities with Proximal Algorithms&lt;/a>, ISIT 2019.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Ling and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Autograding.pdf">Human-Assisted Computation for Auto-grading&lt;/a>, IEEE ICDM Workshop on Machine Learning for Education 2018.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Ling and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/pilotstudy.pdf">Pilot Study on Optimal Task Scheduling in Learning&lt;/a>, ACM Learning at Scale 2018.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. Kuo, C.-N. Hang, P. D.-D. Yu and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/GraphChallenge2018.pdf">Parallel Counting of Triangles in Large Graphs: Pruning and Hierarchical Clustering Algorithms&lt;/a>, IEEE High Performance Extreme Computing MIT-Amazon Graph Challenge (Honorable Mention) 2018.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>P.-D. Yu, C. W. Tan and H. L. Fu, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/graphalgorithms.pdf">Graph Algorithms for Preventing Cascading Failures in Networks&lt;/a>, 52nd CISS 2018 (Invited Paper).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>P.-D. Yu, C. W. Tan and H. Fu, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/acmrumorsourcedetection.pdf">Rumor Source Detection in Finite Graphs with Boundary Effects by Message-passing Algorithms&lt;/a>, ACM/IEEE ASONAM 2017.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>P.-D. Yu, C. W. Tan and H. Fu, Rumor Source Detection in Unicyclic Graphs, Information Theory Workshop 2017.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng, C. Joe-Wong, J. Chen, C. Brinton, C. W. Tan and M. Chiang, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/cloudpricing.pdf">Economic Viability of a Virtual Internet Service Provider&lt;/a>, IEEE INFOCOM 2017.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. Li, X. Guang, C. W. Tan, R. W. Yeung, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/securediversity.pdf">On Secure Asymmetric Multilevel Diversity Coding Systems&lt;/a>, IEEE ISIT, 2017.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. Li, F. Ye, X. Guang, Z. Zhou, C. W. Tan, R. W. Yeung, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/sourcecodingrepair.pdf">On Independent Distributed Source Coding Problems with Exact Repair&lt;/a>, IEEE ITW, 2017.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng, C. Joe-Wong, C. Brinton, C. W. Tan, S. Ha and M. Chiang, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/cloudpricing.pdf">On the Viability of a Cloud Virtual Service Provider&lt;/a>, ACM SIGMETRICS 2016.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, P.-D. Yu, C. Lai, W. Zhang and H. L. Fu, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/CISS2016Facebook.pdf">Optimal Detection of Influential Spreaders in Online Social Networks&lt;/a>, 50th CISS 2016 (Invited Paper).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Bi, C. W. Tan and A. Tang, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Infocom_2016.pdf">Network Utility Maximization with Path Cardinality Constraints&lt;/a>, IEEE INFOCOM 2016.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng, C. Joe-Wong, C. W. Tan, M. Chiang and X. Wang, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/sigcomm.pdf">How to Bid the Cloud?&lt;/a>, ACM SIGCOMM 2015.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng, C. Joe-Wong, C. W. Tan, S. Ha and M. Chiang, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TradedDataPlan_INFOCOM2015.pdf">Secondary Markets for Mobile Data: Feasibility and Benefits of Traded Data Plans&lt;/a>, IEEE INFOCOM 2015.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng and C. W. Tan, A Probabilistic Characterization of the Rumor Graph Boundary in Rumor Source Detection, Proc. of IEEE DSP 2015.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Z. Wang, W. Dong, W. Zhang and C. W. Tan, On Inferring Rumor Source for SIS Model under Multiple Observations, Proc. of IEEE DSP 2015.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Z. Wang, W. Dong, W. Zhang and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/RumorSourceDetection.pdf">Rumor Source Detection with Multiple Observations: Fundamental Limits and Algorithms&lt;/a>, Proc. of ACM SIGMETRICS 2014.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Chen, J. Zhang, X. Wang, X. Tian, W. Wu, F. Wu and C. W. Tan, Secrecy Capacity Scaling of Large-scale Cognitive Networks, Proc. of ACM MobiHoc 2014.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, S. W. Ho, S. Lin and R. W. Yeung, Finding the Capacity of Next-Generation Networks by Linear Programming, IEEE ICCS 2014.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>S. W. Ho, C. W. Tan and R. W. Yeung, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/HoTanYeung_ISIT2014.pdf">Proving and Disproving Information Inequalities&lt;/a>, IEEE Intl. Symp. Information Theory 2014.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/CISS2014.pdf">Wireless Network Optimization by Perron-Frobenius Theory&lt;/a>, 48th CISS 2014 (Invited Paper).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. W. Hong, C. W. Tan, L. Zheng, C. L. Hsieh and C. H. Lee, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/INFOCOM2014_HongTanZhengHsiehLee.pdf">A Unified Framework for Wireless Max-min Utility Optimization with General Monotonic Constraints&lt;/a>, IEEE INFOCOM 2014.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>W. Dong, W. Zhang and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/DongZhangTan_ISIT2013.pdf">Rooting out the Rumor Culprit from Suspects&lt;/a>, Proc. of IEEE Intl. Symp. on Information Theory 2013.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>F. M. F. Wong, C. W. Tan, S. Sen and M. Chiang, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TweetRetweet2013.pdf">Quantifying Political Leaning from Tweets and Retweets&lt;/a>, Seventh International AAAI Conference on Weblogs and Social Media (ICWSM), 2013.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>X. Zhai, L. Zheng, J. Wang and C. W. Tan, Optimization Algorithms for Epidemic Evolution in Broadcast Networks, IEEE WCNC, 2013.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Zheng and C. W. Tan, Optimal Fixed-Point Algorithms for Service Differentiation in Wireless Networks, IEEE WiOpt, 2013.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>X. Zhai, L. Zheng and C. W. Tan, Convex Relaxation Algorithms for Energy-Infeasibility Tradeoff in Cognitive Radio Networks, IEEE WiOpt, 2013.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>X. Lou and C. W. Tan, Convex Relaxation and Decomposition in Large Resistive Power Networks with Energy Storage, IEEE SmartGridComm 2013.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>D. W. H. Cai, C. W. Tan and S. H. Low, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/INFOCOM2012_CaiTanLow.pdf">Optimal Max-min Fairness Rate Control in Wireless Networks: Perron-Frobenius Characterization and Algorithms&lt;/a>, IEEE INFOCOM 2012.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, D. W. H. Cai, and X. Lou, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanCaiLou_SGComm2012.pdf">DC Optimal Power Flow: Uniqueness and Algorithms&lt;/a>, IEEE SmartGridComm 2012 Workshop - Architectures and Modeling for the Smart Grid (Invited Paper).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>N. Chen, T. Quek, and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/ChenQuekTan_SGComm2012.pdf">Optimal Charging of Electric Vehicles in Smart Grid: Characterization and Valley-filling Algorithms&lt;/a>, IEEE SmartGridComm 2012. &lt;a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1208.4743">Longer version&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Huang, C. W. Tan and B. D. Rao, Outage Balancing in Multiuser MISO Networks: Network Duality and Algorithms, IEEE Globecom 2012.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Huang, C. W. Tan and B. D. Rao, Cooperative Beamforming in Multiuser MIMO Networks: Fast SINR Fairness Algorithms, IEEE Globecom 2012.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Huang, C. W. Tan and B. D. Rao, Asymptotic Analysis of Max-min Weighted SINR in Multiuser Downlink, 46th CISS 2012 (Invited Paper).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Huang, C. W. Tan and B. D. Rao, Multicell Network Duality with Instantaneous and Statistical Channel Information, CISS 2012.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Zhao, C. W. Tan, A. S. Avestimehr, S. N. Diggavi and G. J. Pottie, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/YueTanAvestimehrDiggaviPottie-ISIT2011.pdf">On the Sum-Capacity with Successive Decoding in Interference Channels&lt;/a>, IEEE Intl. Symp. Infomartion Theory 2011.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>D. W. H. Cai, T. Quek, C. W. Tan and S. H. Low, Max-min Weighted SINR in Coordinated Multicell MIMO Downlink System, IEEE WiOpt 2011.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>D. W. H. Cai, T. Quek and C. W. Tan, Coordinated Max-Min SIR Optimization in Multicell Downlink - Duality and Algorithm, IEEE ICC 2011.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Tan-INFOCOM2011.pdf">Optimal Power Control in Rayleigh-fading Heterogeneous Networks&lt;/a>, IEEE INFOCOM 2011.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Y. Gao, C. W. Tan, Y. Huang, Z. Zeng and P. R. Kumar, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/GaoTanHuangZengKumar-INFOCOM2011.pdf">Feasibility and Optimization of Delay Guarantees for Non-homogeneous Flows in IEEE 802.11 WLANs&lt;/a>, IEEE INFOCOM 2011.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>L. Yang, H. Kim, J. Zhang, M. Chiang and C. W. Tan, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/YangKimZhangChiangTan-INFOCOM2011.pdf">Pricing-based Spectrum Access Control in Cognitive Radio Networks with Random Access&lt;/a>, IEEE INFOCOM 2011.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>D. W. H. Cai, T. Quek and C. W. Tan, Max-min Weighted SIR for MIMO Downlink System: Optimality and Algorithms, IEEE Intl. Symp. Information Theory 2010.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>M. Wang, C. W. Tan, A. Tang and S. H. Low, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/WangTanTangLow_Globecom2009.pdf">How Bad is Single Path Routing?&lt;/a> IEEE GLOBECOM 2009.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, S. Friedland and S. H. Low, Maximizing Sum Rates in Multiuser Communication Systems: Theory and Algorithms, ISMP 2009.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, M. Chiang and R. Srikant, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanChiangSrikant_ISIT2009.pdf">Maximizing Sum Rate and Minimizing MSE on Multiuser Downlink: Optimality, Fast Algorithms, and Equivalence via Max-min SIR&lt;/a>, IEEE ISIT 2009.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, M. Chiang and R. Srikant, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanChiangSrikant_INFOCOM2009.pdf">Fast Algorithms and Performance Bounds for Sum Rate Maximization in Wireless Networks&lt;/a>, IEEE INFOCOM 2009.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>P. Tsiaflakis, C. W. Tan, Y. Yi, M. Chiang and M. Moonen, Optimality Certificate of Dynamic Spectrum Management in Multi-Carrier Interference Channels, IEEE ISIT 2008.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, D. P. Palomar and M. Chiang, &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/TanPalomarChiang_INFOCOM2007.pdf">Exploiting Hidden Convexity for Flexible and Robust Resource Allocation in Cellular Networks&lt;/a>, IEEE INFOCOM 2007.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, D. P. Palomar and M. Chiang, Distributed Optimization of Coupled Systems with Applications to Network Utility Maximization, IEEE ICASSP 2006.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>C. W. Tan, D. P. Palomar and M. Chiang, Solving Nonconvex Power Control Problems in Wireless Networks: Low SIR Regime and Distributed Algorithms, IEEE GLOBECOM 2005.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/research/</guid><description>&lt;style>
img.float-right {
 max-width: 300px;
 width: 60%;
 float: right;
 margin-left: 2em;
}

.openings {
 padding: 1em;
 border: 1px solid #ccc;
 border-radius: 8px;
 background-color: #f9f9f9;
 margin-bottom: 2em;
}

&lt;/style>
&lt;!-- &lt;div class="openings">
&lt;h3 style="margin-top: 0; font-weight: bold; font-size: 1rem;">Postdoctoral Fellow and Ph.D. student openings:&lt;/h3>

&lt;ul style="font-size: 0.875rem;">
&lt;li>(1) Convex optimization and distributed machine learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(2) Artificial Intelligence in Networks (e.g., Large Language Models for wireless and social networks)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;br>
&lt;span style="font-size: 0.875rem;">
Candidates are expected to be proficient in mathematics (e.g., linear algebra, convex optimization) and have good software programming experience. Please email at &lt;b>cheewei.tan @ ntu.edu.sg&lt;/b> with CV and transcripts.
&lt;/span>
&lt;/div> -->
&lt;h1 id="research">Research&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="1-large-language-model-and-gen-ai-research">(1) Large Language Model and Gen-AI Research&lt;/h2>
&lt;!-- &lt;img src="https://cheewtan.github.io/images/deeptrace.jpg" class="float-right"> -->
&lt;p>Our research in generative AI technology spans from exploring novel statistical techniques to understand large language models (LLMs), particularly within the domain of natural language processing for AI-assisted programming [1-3]. We are currently focused on unsupervised learning with human-in-the-loop, using optimization-theoretic and information-theoretic techniques to develop robust solutions that address AI fairness and safety. Additionally, we are studying the benchmarking [4] and ranking of LLM agents, such as copilots and chatbots, and exploring retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) to evaluate and rank their performance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Short Introduction</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/homepage/short-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/homepage/short-introduction/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Teaching</title><link>https://cheewtan.github.io/teaching-and-outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:31:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://cheewtan.github.io/teaching-and-outreach/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="teaching">Teaching&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>1. &lt;strong>Convex Optimization and its Applications in Computer Science&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/CSCVXClass/index.htm">Course Webpage&lt;/a>, project ref: &lt;a href="https://jemnz.com/lp75.html">Extremely short linear program solvers&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2. &lt;strong>Artificial Intelligence: Past, Present, Future&lt;/strong> | &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec_AI_CourseIntro.pdf">Introduction&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec1_AI_Birth.pdf">Lec 1&lt;/a> Birth of AI | &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec2_LogicBoole.pdf">Lec 2&lt;/a> Mathematical Logic in AI | &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec3_AIGames.pdf">Lec 3&lt;/a> AI Games | &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec4_AIGamesSearch.pdf">Lec 4&lt;/a> AI Games and Search | &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec5_MazeSolving.pdf">Lec 5&lt;/a>Maze-Solving and Retros | &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec_Crowdsourcing.pdf">Lec 6&lt;/a> Human-assisted Computation | &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec_Juggling.pdf">Lec 7&lt;/a> Robots |  &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec_AIChatbot.pdf">Lec 8&lt;/a> AI Chatbots | &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec_AIArt.pdf">Lec 9&lt;/a> Neural Network Applications | &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec_AutomatedReasoning.pdf">Lec 10&lt;/a> Automated Reasoning | &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec_MachineLearning.pdf">Lec 11&lt;/a>Machine Learning | &lt;a href="https://cheewtan.github.io/resources/Lec_Review.pdf">Lec 13&lt;/a> Review &lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>